<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc SYSTEM "doc.dtd">
<doc title="Examples &amp; Use Cases - Crunchy Containers for PostgreSQL">
<description>Examples &amp; Use Cases - Crunchy Containers for PostgreSQL</description>
<section id="_usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<p>Here are some useful resources for finding the right commands to troubleshoot &amp; modify containers in
the various environments shown in this guide:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
<link url="http://www.bogotobogo.com/DevOps/Docker/Docker-Cheat-Sheet.php">Docker Cheat Sheet</link>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<link url="https://kubernetes.io/docs/user-guide/kubectl-cheatsheet/">Kubectl Cheat Sheet</link>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<link url="https://github.com/nekop/openshift-sandbox/blob/master/docs/command-cheatsheet.md">OpenShift Cheat Sheet</link>
</list-item>
<list-item>
<link url="https://github.com/kubernetes/helm/blob/master/docs/using_helm.md">Helm Cheat Sheet</link>
</list-item>
</list>
<section id="_docker_customized_configuration">
<title>Docker Customized Configuration</title>
<p>You can use your own version of the setup.sql SQL file to customize
the initialization of database data and objects when the container and
database are created.</p>
<p>This example can be run as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/custom-setup
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>This works by placing a file named, setup.sql, within the /pgconf mounted volume
directory.  Portions of the setup.sql file are required for the crunchy container
to work, see comments within the sample setup.sql file.</p>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_environment_setup">
<title>Kubernetes Environment Setup</title>
<p>This section will illustrate how to set up a new Kubernetes namespace called <b>demo</b>, and will
then show how to provide permissions to that namespace to allow the Kubernetes examples to run
within that namespace.</p>
<p>First, view currently existing namespaces:</p>
<code-block>$ kubectl get namespace
NAME          STATUS    AGE
default       Active    21d
kube-public   Active    21d
kube-system   Active    21d</code-block>
<p>Then, create a new namespace called <b>demo</b>:</p>
<code-block>$ kubectl create namespace demo
namespace "demo" created
$ kubectl get namespace demo
NAME      STATUS    AGE
demo      Active    7s</code-block>
<p>Then we'll set the namespace as our current location:</p>
<code-block>$ kubectl config set-context $(kubectl config current-context) --namespace=demo</code-block>
<p>We can verify that the namespace was set correctly through the following command:</p>
<code-block>$ kubectl config view | grep namespace:
    namespace: demo</code-block>
<p>We shall now create a user account named that will be responsible for managing Kubernetes
resources within the namespace we have created.</p>
<p>Follow the instructions located <link url="https://docs.bitnami.com/kubernetes/how-to/configure-rbac-in-your-kubernetes-cluster/#use-case-1-create-user-with-limited-namespace-access">here</link>
to create a new user account with limited permissions for your namespace. Steps 2-5 will
be sufficient to explain.</p>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_environment_setup_amp_configuration">
<title>OpenShift Environment Setup &amp; Configuration</title>
<p>This section will illustrate how to set up a new OpenShift project called <b>demo</b>, and will
additionally show how to create a new <b>demo</b> user who has the proper privileges to run OpenShift
examples within that project under that user.</p>
<p>First we will create a new project as the standard <b>developer</b> user that you are logged into
upon running <b>oc cluster up</b>:</p>
<code-block>$ oc new-project demo --description="Crunchy Containers project" --display-name="Crunchy-Containers"
Now using project "demo" on server "https://127.0.0.1:8443".

You can add applications to this project with the 'new-app' command. For example, try:

    oc new-app centos/ruby-22-centos7~https://github.com/openshift/ruby-ex.git

to build a new example application in Ruby.</code-block>
<p>If we view the list of projects, we can see the new project has been added and is <quote>active</quote>.</p>
<code-block>$ oc get projects
NAME        DISPLAY NAME         STATUS
demo        Crunchy-Containers   Active
myproject   My Project           Active</code-block>
<p>If you were on a different project and wanted to switch to the demo project, you would do
so by running the following:</p>
<code-block>$ oc project demo
Now using project "demo" on server "https://127.0.0.1:8443".</code-block>
<p>At this point we'll create a new user - foo. Logging in using this method will automatically
create a new user with the authentication method of <b>anypassword</b>, meaning that you can simply
hit enter to login.</p>
<code-block>$ oc login -u foo
Authentication required for https://127.0.0.1:8443 (openshift)
Username: foo
Password:
Login successful.

You don't have any projects. You can try to create a new project, by running

    oc new-project &lt;projectname&gt;</code-block>
<p>Notice that there are no projects that <b>foo</b> currently has access to. We'll fix that
by first logging in as the <b>system:admin</b> user.</p>
<code-block>$ oc login -u system:admin
Logged into "https://127.0.0.1:8443" as "system:admin" using existing credentials.

You have access to the following projects and can switch between them with 'oc project &lt;projectname&gt;':

  * default
    demo
    kube-public
    kube-system
    myproject
    openshift
    openshift-infra

Using project "default".</code-block>
<p>If we view the list of users, <b>foo</b> has been added.</p>
<code-block>$ oc get user
NAME        UID                                    FULL NAME   IDENTITIES
developer   c818ca4f-c5b4-11e7-9e42-0800278f57e4               anypassword:developer
foo         5879a850-c5b5-11e7-9e42-0800278f57e4               anypassword:foo</code-block>
<p>We want foo to be able to access the <b>demo</b> project and have administrative access.</p>
<code-block>$ oc adm policy add-role-to-user admin foo -n demo
role "admin" added: "foo"</code-block>
<p>To verify it is working correctly, log in as foo:</p>
<code-block>$ oc login -u foo
Logged into "https://127.0.0.1:8443" as "foo" using existing credentials.

You have one project on this server: "demo"

Using project "demo".</code-block>
<p>The <b>demo</b> project has now been added to this user's list of existing projects, and
new clusters will be created within this project.</p>
<p>More information on authorizing users and managing clusters can be found
<link url="https://docs.openshift.com/container-platform/3.6/admin_guide/manage_users.html">here</link>.</p>
<section id="_custom_configuration">
<title>Custom Configuration</title>
<p>This example shows how you can use your own customized version of setup.sql
when creating a PostgreSQL database container in OpenShift.</p>
<p>If you mount a /pgconf volume, crunchy-postgres will look at that directory
for postgresql.conf, pg_hba.conf, and setup.sql.  If it finds one of them it
will use that file instead of the default files.  Currently, if you specify a postgresql.conf
file, you also need to specify a pg_hba.conf file.</p>
<p>The example shows how a custom setup.sql file can be used.
Run it as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/custom-config
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>This will start a database container that will use an NFS mounted /pgconf
directory that will container the custom setup.sql file found in the example
directory.</p>
<section id="_customized_configuration_with_synchronous_replica">
<title>Customized Configuration with Synchronous Replica</title>
<p>This example shows how you can use your own customized version of postgresql.conf
and pg_hba.conf to override the default configuration.  It also specifies
a synchronous replica in the postgresql.conf and starts it up upon creation.</p>
<p>Run it as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/custom-config-sync
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>This will start a <b>csprimary</b> container that will use the custom
config files when the database is running.  It will also create
a synchronous replica named <b>cssyncreplica</b>. This replica is then
connected to the primary via streaming replication.</p>
</section>
<section id="_configmap_database_credentials">
<title>Configmap Database Credentials</title>
<p>This example shows how to use a configmap to store the
postgresql.conf and pg_hba.conf files to be used when
overriding the default configuration within the container.</p>
<p>Start by running the database container:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/configmap
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>The files pg_hba.conf and postgresql.conf in the
example directory are used to create a configmap object
within OpenShift.  Within the run.sh script, the configmap
is created. Notice within the configmap.json file
how the /pgconf mount is related to the configmap.</p>
</section>
<section id="_templates_configuration">
<title>Templates Configuration</title>
<p>An example of using OpenShift Templates to build pods, routes, services, etc can be
found in the following directory:</p>
<code-block>$CCPROOT/examples/openshift/workshop</code-block>
<p>You use the <b>oc new-app</b> command to create objects from the
JSON templates.  This is an alternative way to create OpenShift objects
instead of using <b>oc create</b>.</p>
<p>See the README file within the workshop directory for instructions
on running the example.</p>
</section>
<section id="_secrets">
<title>Secrets</title>
<p>You can use Kubernetes Secrets to set and maintain your database
credentials.  Secrets requires you base64 encode your user and password
values as follows:</p>
<code-block>echo -n 'myuserid' | base64</code-block>
<p>You will paste these values into  your JSON secrets files for values.</p>
<p>This example allows you to set the PostgreSQL passwords
using Kubernetes Secrets.</p>
<p>The secret uses a base64 encoded string to represent the
values to be read by the container during initialization.  The
encoded password value is <b>password</b>.  Run the example
as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/secret
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>The secrets are mounted in the <b>/pguser</b>, <b>/pgprimary</b>, <b>/pgroot</b> volumes within the
container and read during initialization.  The container
scripts create a PostgreSQL user with those values, and sets the passwords
for the primary user and PostgreSQL superuser using the mounted secret volumes.</p>
<p>When using secrets, you do NOT have to specify the following
environment variables if you specify all three secrets volumes:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
PG_USER
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_PASSWORD
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_ROOT_PASSWORD
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_PRIMARY_USER
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_PRIMARY_PASSWORD
</list-item>
</list>
<p>You can test the container as follows, in all cases, the password is <b>password</b>:</p>
<code-block>psql -h secret-pg -U pguser1 postgres
psql -h secret-pg -U postgres postgres
psql -h secret-pg -U primary postgres</code-block>
<p>Secrets requires you base64 encode your user and password
values as follows:</p>
<code-block>echo -n 'myuserid' | base64</code-block>
<p>You can paste these values into your JSON secrets files for values.</p>
</section>
<section id="_ssl_authentication">
<title>SSL Authentication</title>
<p>This example shows how you can configure PostgreSQL to use SSL for
client authentication.</p>
<p>The example requires SSL keys to be created and the example script
<b>keys.sh</b> is required to be executed to create the required
server and client certificates. This script also creates
a client key configuration you can use to test with.</p>
<p>The example requires an NFS volume, /pgconf, be mounted into which
the PostgreSQL configuration files and keys are copied to.  Permissions
of the keys are important as well, they will need to be owned
by either the <b>root</b> or <b>postgres</b> user.  The <b>run.sh</b> script
copies the required files and sets these permissions when executing the example.</p>
<p>The <b>keys.sh</b> script creates a client cert with the <b>testuser</b> specified
as the CN.  The <b>testuser</b> PostgreSQL user is created by the <b>setup.sql</b>
configuration script as normal.  It is with the <b>testuser</b> role that
you will test with.</p>
<p>Run the PostgreSQL example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/customer-config-ssl
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>A required step to make this example work is to define
in your <b>/etc/hosts</b> file an entry that maps <b>server.crunchydata.com</b>
to the example's service IP address, this is because we generate
a server certificate with the server name of <b>server.crunchyhdata.com</b>.</p>
<p>For example, if your service has an address as follows:</p>
<code-block> oc get service
NAME                CLUSTER-IP       EXTERNAL-IP   PORT(S)                   AGE
custom-config-ssl   172.30.211.108   &lt;none&gt;        5432/TCP</code-block>
<p>Then your <b>/etc/hosts</b> file needs an entry like this:</p>
<code-block>172.30.211.108 server.crunchydata.com</code-block>
<p>For a production Openshift installation, you'll likely want DNS
names to resolve to the PostgreSQL Service name and generate
server certificates using the DNS names instead of an example
name like <b>server.crunchydata.com</b>.</p>
<p>Once the container starts up, you can test the SSL connection
as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h server.crunchydata.com -U testuser userdb</code-block>
<p>You should see a connection that looks like the following:</p>
<code-block>psql (9.6.3)
SSL connection (protocol: TLSv1.2, cipher: ECDHE-RSA-AES256-GCM-SHA384, bits: 256, compression: off)
Type "help" for help.

userdb=&gt;</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_tips">
<title>Tips</title>
<section id="_postgresql_passwords">
<title>PostgreSQL Passwords</title>
<p>The passwords used for the PostgreSQL user accounts are generated
by the OpenShift <i>process</i> command.  To inspect what value was
supplied, you can inspect the primary pod as follows:</p>
<code-block>oc get pod pr-primary -o json | grep PG</code-block>
<p>Look for the values of the environment variables:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
PG_USER
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_PASSWORD
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_DATABASE
</list-item>
</list>
</section>
<section id="_password_management">
<title>Password Management</title>
<p>When you backup a database, the original user IDs and password credentials
are copied over from the original database and saved. Because of this, you
cannot use generated passwords as the new passwords will not be the same as the
passwords stored in the backup.</p>
<p>You have various options to deal with managing your
passwords:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
externalize your passwords using secrets instead of using generated values
</list-item>
<list-item>
manually update your passwords to your known values after a restore
</list-item>
</list>
<admonition type="note">Environment variables can be modified when there is a a deployment
controller in use. Currently, only the replicas have a deployment controller in
order to avoid the possibility of creating multiple primaries.</admonition>
<code-block>oc env dc/pg-primary-rc PG_PRIMARY_PASSWORD=foo PG_PRIMARY=user1</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_examine_backup_logs">
<title>Examine Backup Logs</title>
<p>Database backups are implemented as a Kubernetes Job. These are meant to run one time only
and not be restarted by Kubernetes. To view jobs in OpenShift you enter:</p>
<code-block>oc get jobs
oc describe job backupjob</code-block>
<p>You can get detailed logs by referring to the pod identifier in the job <i>describe</i>
output as follows:</p>
<code-block>oc logs backupjob-pxh2o</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_backups">
<title>Backups</title>
<p>Backups require the use of network storage like NFS in OpenShift.
There is a required order of using NFS volumes in the manner
we do database backups.</p>
<p>There is a one-to-one relationship between a PV (persistent volume) and a PVC
(persistence volume claim).  You can NOT have a one-to-many relationship between
PV and PVC(s).</p>
<p>So, to do a database backup repeatedly, this general pattern will need to be followed.</p>
<list>
<list-item>
as OpenShift admin user, create a unique PV (e.g. backup-pv-mydatabase)
</list-item>
<list-item>
as a project user, create a unique PVC (e.g. backup-pvc-mydatabase)
</list-item>
<list-item>
reference the unique PVC within the backup-job template
</list-item>
<list-item>
execute the backup job template
</list-item>
<list-item>
as a project user, delete the job
</list-item>
<list-item>
as a project user, delete the PVC
</list-item>
<list-item>
as OpenShift admin user, delete the unique PV
</list-item>
</list>
<p>This procedure will need to be scripted and executed by the devops team when
performing a database backup.</p>
</section>
<section id="_restores">
<title>Restores</title>
<p>To perform a database restore, we do the following:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
locate the NFS path to the database backup we want to restore with
</list-item>
<list-item>
edit a PV to use that NFS path
</list-item>
<list-item>
edit a PV to specify a unique label
</list-item>
<list-item>
create the PV
</list-item>
<list-item>
edit a PVC to use the previously created PV, specifying the same label
   used in the PV
</list-item>
<list-item>
edit a database template, specifying the PVC to be used for mounting
   to the /backup directory in the database pod
</list-item>
<list-item>
create the database pod
</list-item>
</list>
<p>If the /pgdata directory is blank AND the /backup directory contains
a valid PostgreSQL backup, it is assumed the user wants to perform a
database restore.</p>
<p>The restore logic will copy /backup files to /pgdata before starting
the database.  It will take time for the copying of the files to
occur since this might be a large amount of data and the volumes
might be on slow networks. You can view the logs of the database pod
to measure the copy progress.</p>
</section>
<section id="_log_aggregation">
<title>Log Aggregation</title>
<p>OpenShift can be configured to include the EFK stack for log aggregation.
OpenShift Administrators can configure the EFK stack as documented
here:</p>
<p><link url="https://docs.openshift.com/enterprise/3.1/install_config/aggregate_logging.html">https://docs.openshift.com/enterprise/3.1/install_config/aggregate_logging.html</link></p>
</section>
<section id="_nss_wrapper">
<title>nss_wrapper</title>
<p>If an OpenShift deployment requires that random generated UIDs be
supported by containers, the Crunchy containers can be modified
similar to those located here to support the use of nss_wrapper
to equate the random generated UIDs/GIDs by OpenShift with
the postgres user.</p>
<p><link url="https://github.com/openshift/postgresql/blob/master/9.4/root/usr/share/container-scripts/postgresql/common.sh">https://github.com/openshift/postgresql/blob/master/9.4/root/usr/share/container-scripts/postgresql/common.sh</link></p>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_container_examples">
<title>Container Examples</title>
<section id="_running_a_single_database">
<title>Running a Single Database</title>
<p>This example starts a single PostgreSQL container and service, the most simple
of examples.</p>
<p>The container creates a default database called <b>userdb</b>, a default user called <b>testuser</b>
and a default password of <b>password</b>.</p>
<p>For all environments, the script additionally creates:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
A persistent volume claim
</list-item>
<list-item>
A container named <b>basic</b>
</list-item>
<list-item>
The database using predefined environment variables
</list-item>
</list>
<p>And specifically for the Kubernetes and OpenShift environments:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
A pod named <b>basic</b>
</list-item>
<list-item>
A service named <b>basic</b>
</list-item>
</list>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>To create the example and run the container:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/basic
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Connect from your local host as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h localhost -p 12000 -U testuser -W userdb</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>To create the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/basic
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Connect from your local host as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h basic -U postgres postgres</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_helm">
<title>Helm</title>
<p>This example resides under the $CCPROOT/examples/helm directory. View the README to run this
example using Helm <link url="https://github.com/CrunchyData/crunchy-containers/blob/master/examples/helm/basic/README.md">here</link>.</p>
</section>
<section id="_openshift">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>To create the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/basic
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Connect from your local host as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h basic.openshift.svc.cluster.local -U testuser userdb</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_creating_a_primary_database_with_pvc">
<title>Creating a Primary Database with PVC</title>
<p>The other example <b>basic</b> uses emptyDir volumes for persistence; if it is desired to
create a PVC based volume to store the PostgreSQL data files for a single primary pod,
run the following example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/primary-pvc
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_creating_a_primary_replica_database_cluster">
<title>Creating a Primary / Replica Database Cluster</title>
<p>This example starts a primary and a replica pod containing a PostgreSQL database.</p>
<p>The container creates a default database called <b>userdb</b>, a default user called
<b>testuser</b> and a default password of <b>password</b>.</p>
<p>For the Docker environment, the script additionally creates:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
A docker volume using the local driver for the primary
</list-item>
<list-item>
A docker volume using the local driver for the replica
</list-item>
<list-item>
A container named <b>primary</b> binding to port 12007
</list-item>
<list-item>
A container named <b>replica</b> binding to port 12008
</list-item>
<list-item>
A mapping of the PostgreSQL port 5432 within the container to the localhost port 12000
</list-item>
<list-item>
The database using predefined environment variables
</list-item>
</list>
<p>And specifically for the Kubernetes and OpenShift environments:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
emptyDir volumes for persistence
</list-item>
<list-item>
A pod named <b>primary</b>
</list-item>
<list-item>
A pod named <b>replica</b>
</list-item>
<list-item>
A service named <b>primary</b>
</list-item>
<list-item>
A service named <b>replica</b>
</list-item>
<list-item>
The database using predefined environment variables
</list-item>
</list>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_2">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>To create the example and run the container:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/primary-replica
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Connect from your local host as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h localhost -p 12007 -U testuser -W userdb
psql -h localhost -p 12008 -U testuser -W userdb</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_docker_compose">
<title>Docker-Compose</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/compose/primary-replica
docker-compose up</code-block>
<p>To deploy more than one replica, run the following:</p>
<code-block>docker-compose up --scale db-replica=3</code-block>
<p>To psql into the created database containers, first identify the ports exposed
on the containers:</p>
<code-block>docker ps</code-block>
<p>Next, using psql, connect to the service:</p>
<code-block>psql -d userdb -h 0.0.0.0 -p &lt;CONTAINER_PORT&gt; -U testuser</code-block>
<admonition type="note">See <b>PG_PASSWORD</b> in <b>docker-compose.yml</b> for the user password.</admonition>
<p>To tear down the example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>docker-compose stop
docker-compose rm</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_2">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Run the following command to deploy a primary and replica database cluster:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/primary-replica
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>It takes about a minute for the replica to begin replicating with the
primary.  To test out replication, see if replication is underway
with this command:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pr-primary -U postgres postgres -c 'table pg_stat_replication'</code-block>
<p>If you see a line returned from that query it means the primary is replicating
to the replica.  Try creating some data on the primary:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pr-primary -U postgres postgres -c 'create table foo (id int)'
psql -h pr-primary -U postgres postgres -c 'insert into foo values (1)'</code-block>
<p>Then verify that the data is replicated to the replica:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pr-replica -U postgres postgres -c 'table foo'</code-block>
<p><b>primary-replica-dc</b></p>
<p>If you wanted to experiment with scaling up the number of replicas, you can run the following example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/primary-replica-dc
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>You can verify that replication is working using the same commands as above.</p>
<p>This example creates 2 replicas when it initially starts.  To scale
up the number of replicas and view what the deployment looks like before and after, run these commands:</p>
<code-block>kubectl get deployment
kubectl scale --current-replicas=2 --replicas=3 deployment/replica-dc
kubectl get deployment
kubectl get pod</code-block>
<p>You can verify that you now have 3 replicas by running this query
on the primary:</p>
<code-block>psql -h primary-dc -U postgres postgres -c 'table pg_stat_replication'</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_helm_2">
<title>Helm</title>
<p>This example resides under the $CCPROOT/examples/helm directory. View the README to run this example
using Helm <link url="https://github.com/CrunchyData/crunchy-containers/blob/master/examples/helm/primary-replica/README.md">here</link>.</p>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_2">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Run the following command to deploy a primary and replica database cluster:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/primary-replica
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>You can then connect to the database instance as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pr-primary -U testuser -W userdb</code-block>
<p><b>primary-replica-dc</b></p>
<p>The primary-replica example creates a primary and non-scaling replica; if you wanted to experiment
with scaling replicas, try the primary-replica-dc example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/primary-replica-dc
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Connect to the PostgreSQL instances with the following:</p>
<code-block>psql -h primary-dc.pgproject.svc.cluster.local -U testuser userdb
psql -h replica-dc.pgproject.svc.cluster.local -U testuser userdb</code-block>
<p>Here is an example of increasing or scaling up the PostgreSQL <i>replica</i> pods to 2:</p>
<code-block>oc scale rc replica-dc-1 --replicas=2</code-block>
<p>Enter the following commands to verify the PostgreSQL replication is working:</p>
<code-block>psql -c 'table pg_stat_replication' -h primary-dc.pgproject.svc.cluster.local -U primary postgres
psql -h replica-dc.pgproject.svc.cluster.local -U primary postgres</code-block>
<p>The replica service is load balancing between multiple replicas; this can be shown by running this
command multiple times and the IP address should alternate between the replicas:</p>
<code-block>psql -h replica-dc -U postgres postgres -c 'select inet_server_addr()'</code-block>
<p><b>primary-replica-rc-pvc</b></p>
<p>The previous primary-replica deployments used emptyDir volumes for persistence. This example uses
a PVC based volume in your NFS directory for the primary and the replicas.</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/primary-replica-rc-pvc
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Upon examining the configured NFS directory, the PostgreSQL data directories that are created
and used by the primary and replica pods are visible. Testing the example uses the same commands
as above, substituting the name <b>primary-replica-rc-pvc</b>.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_primary_replica_deployment">
<title>Primary / Replica Deployment</title>
<p>Starting in release 1.2.8, the PostgreSQL container can accept
an environment variable named PGDATA_PATH_OVERRIDE.  If set,
the /pgdata/subdir path will use a path subdir name of your
choosing instead of the default which is the hostname of the container.</p>
<p>This example shows how a Deployment of a PostgreSQL primary is
supported. A pod is a deployment that uses a hostname generated by
Kubernetes; because of this, a new hostname will be defined upon
restart of the primary pod.</p>
<p>For finding the /pgdata that pertains to the pod, you will need
to specify a /pgdata/subdir name that never changes. This requirement is
handled by the PGDATA_PATH_OVERRIDE environment variable.</p>
<p>The container creates a default database called <b>userdb</b>, a default user called
<b>testuser</b> and a default password of <b>password</b>.</p>
<p>This example will create the following in your Kubernetes and OpenShift environments:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
primary-dc service, uses a PVC to persist PostgreSQL data
</list-item>
<list-item>
replica-dc service, uses emptyDir persistence
</list-item>
<list-item>
primary-dc Deployment of replica count 1 for the primary
   PostgreSQL database pod
</list-item>
<list-item>
replica-dc Deployment of replica count 1 for the replica
</list-item>
<list-item>
replica2-dc Deployment of replica count 1 for the 2nd replica
</list-item>
<list-item>
ConfigMap to hold a custom postgresql.conf, setup.sql, and
   pg_hba.conf files
</list-item>
<list-item>
Secrets for the primary user, superuser, and normal user to
   hold the passwords
</list-item>
<list-item>
Volume mount for /pgbackrest and /pgwal
</list-item>
</list>
<p>The persisted data for the PostgreSQL primary is found under /pgdata/primary-dc.
If you delete the primary pod, the Deployment will create another
pod for the primary, and will be able to start up immediately since
we are using the same /pgdata/primary-dc data directory.</p>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_kubernetes_3">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Start the example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/primary-deployment
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_3">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Start the example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/primary-deployment
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_automated_failover">
<title>Automated Failover</title>
<p>This example shows how to run the crunchy-watch container
to perform an automated failover.  For the example to
work, the host on which you are running needs to allow
read-write access to /run/docker.sock.  The crunchy-watch
container runs as the <b>postgres</b> user, so adjust the
file permissions of /run/docker.sock accordingly.</p>
<p>The <b>primary-replica</b> example is required to be run before this example.</p>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_3">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>Run the example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/watch
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>This will start the watch container which tests every few seconds
whether the primary database is running, if not, it will
trigger a failover (using docker exec) on the replica host.</p>
<p>Test it out by stopping the primary:</p>
<code-block>docker stop primary
docker logs watch</code-block>
<p>Look at the watch container logs to see it perform the failover.</p>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_4">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/watch
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Check out the log of the watch container as follows:</p>
<code-block>kubectl log watch</code-block>
<p>Then trigger a failover using this command:</p>
<code-block>kubectl delete pod primary</code-block>
<p>Resume watching the watch container's log and verify that it
detects the primary is not reachable and performs a failover
on the replica.</p>
<p>A final test is to see if the old replica is now a fully functioning
primary by inserting some test data into it as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h primary -U postgres postgres -c 'create table failtest (id int)'</code-block>
<p>The above command still works because the watch container has
changed the labels of the replica to make it a primary, so the primary
service will still work and route now to the new primary even though
the pod is named replica.</p>
<p><b>Tip</b></p>
<p>You can view the labels on a pod with this command:</p>
<code-block>kubectl describe pod replica | grep Label</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_4">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>First, create an OpenShift service account which is used by the crunchy-watch
container to perform the failover. Also, set policies that allow the
service account the ability to edit resources within the OpenShift and
default projects.</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/watch
oc create -f watch-sa.json
oc policy add-role-to-group edit system:serviceaccounts -n openshift
oc policy add-role-to-group edit system:serviceaccounts -n default</code-block>
<p>Next, create the container that will <i>watch</i> the PostgreSQL cluster:</p>
<code-block>./run.sh</code-block>
<p>At this point, the watcher will sleep every 20 seconds (configurable) to
see if the primary is responding. If the primary doesn't respond, the watcher
will perform the following logic:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
log into OpenShift using the service account
</list-item>
<list-item>
set its current project
</list-item>
<list-item>
find the first replica pod
</list-item>
<list-item>
delete the primary service saving off the primary service definition
</list-item>
<list-item>
create the trigger file on the first replica pod
</list-item>
<list-item>
wait 20 seconds for the failover to complete on the replica pod
</list-item>
<list-item>
edit the replica pod's label to match that of the primary
</list-item>
<list-item>
recreate the primary service using the stored service definition
</list-item>
<list-item>
loop through the other remaining replica and delete its pod
</list-item>
</list>
<p>At this point, clients when access the primary's service will actually
be accessing the new primary.  Also, OpenShift will recreate the number
of replicas to its original configuration which each replica pointed to the
new primary.  Replication from the primary to the new replicas will be
started as each new replica is started by OpenShift.</p>
<p>To test it out, delete the primary pod and view the watch pod log:</p>
<code-block>oc delete pod primary-dc
oc logs watch
oc get pod</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_performing_a_backup_amp_restore">
<title>Performing a Backup &amp; Restore</title>
<p>The script assumes you are going to backup the <b>basic</b>
container created in the first example, so you need to ensure
that container is running. This example assumes you have configured NFS as described
in the <link url="install.adoc">installation documentation</link>. Things to point out with this example
include its use of persistent volumes and volume claims to store the backup data files to
an NFS server.</p>
<p>A successful backup will perform pg_basebackup on the pg-primary and store
the backup in the NFS mounted volume under a directory named pg-primary. Each
backup will be stored in a subdirectory with a timestamp as the name, allowing any number of backups to be kept.</p>
<p>The backup script will do the following:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
Start up a backup container named basicbackup
</list-item>
<list-item>
Run pg_basebackup on the container named primary
</list-item>
<list-item>
Store the backup in /tmp/backups/primary directory
</list-item>
<list-item>
Exit after the backup
</list-item>
</list>
<p>When you are ready to restore from the backup, the restore example runs a PostgreSQL container
passing in the backup location. The startup of the container will use rsync to copy the backup
data to this new container, and then launch PostgreSQL which will use the backup data to start.</p>
<p>The restore script will do the following:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
Start up a container named primary-restore
</list-item>
<list-item>
Copy the backup files from the previous backup example into /pgdata
</list-item>
<list-item>
Start up the container using the backup files
</list-item>
<list-item>
Map the PostgreSQL port of 5432 in the container to your local host port of 12001
</list-item>
</list>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_4">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>Run the backup with this command:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/backup
./run.sh</code-block>
<p><b>primary-restore</b></p>
<p>When you are ready to restore from the backup created, run the following example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/restore
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_5">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/backup-job
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>The Kubernetes Job type executes a pod and then the pod exits.  You can
view the Job status using this command:</p>
<code-block>kubectl get job</code-block>
<p>You should find the backup archive in this location:</p>
<code-block>ls /mnt/nfsfileshare/basic</code-block>
<p><b>primary-restore</b></p>
<p>When ready to restore, you will need the timestamped directory path under
/mnt/nfsfileshare/basic in order to locate the backup to use. Edit the primary-restore.json
file and update the BACKUP_PATH setting to specify the NFS backup path you want to restore with.</p>
<code-block>"name": "BACKUP_PATH",
"value": "basic/2016-05-27-14-35-33"</code-block>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/primary-restore
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Test the restored database as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h restored-primary -U postgres postgres</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_5">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Start the backup:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/backup-job
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>The <b>examples/openshift/crunchy-pv-backup.json</b> specifies a <b>persistentVolumeReclaimPolicy</b>
of <b>Retain</b> to tell OpenShift that we want to keep the volume contents after the removal of the PV.</p>
<p><b>primary-restore</b></p>
<p>When ready to restore, you will need the timestamped directory path under
/mnt/nfsfileshare/basic in order to locate the backup to use. Edit the primary-restore.json
file and update the BACKUP_PATH setting to specify the NFS backup path you want to restore with.</p>
<code-block>"name": "BACKUP_PATH",
"value": "basic/2016-05-27-14-35-33"</code-block>
<p>Then create the pod:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/primary-restore
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>When the database pod starts, it will copy the backup files
to the database directory inside the pod and start up postgres as
usual.</p>
<p>The restore only takes place if:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
the /pgdata directory is empty
</list-item>
<list-item>
the /backups directory contains a valid postgresql.conf file
</list-item>
</list>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_pgbackrest">
<title>pgbackrest</title>
<p>Starting in release 1.3.1, the <b>pgbackrest</b> utility has been
added to the crunchy-postgres container.  See the
<link url="backrest.adoc">pgbackrest Documentation</link> for details
on how this feature works within the Crunchy Container Suite.</p>
</section>
<section id="_pgadmin4">
<title>pgadmin4</title>
<p>This example deploys the pgadmin4 (beta4) web user interface
for PostgreSQL.</p>
<p>After running the example, you should be able to browse to <link url="http://127.0.0.1:5050">http://127.0.0.1:5050</link>
and log into the web application using a user ID of <b>admin@admin.org</b>
and password of <b>password</b>. If you are running this example using Kubernetes or
OpenShift, replace <b>127.0.0.1</b> with the IP address of the created service.</p>
<p>The example uses pgadmin4 configuration files which are mounted
at an NFS mount point. This NFS data directory is mounted into
the container and used by the pgadmin4 application to persist
Metadata.</p>
<p>See the <link url="http://pgadmin.org">pgadmin4 documentation</link> for more details.</p>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_5">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>To run this example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/pgadmin4
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_6">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Start the container as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/pgadmin4
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_6">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>To run this example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/pgadmin4
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_proxy">
<title>Proxy</title>
<p>A <b>crunchy-proxy</b> example is provided that will run a container that creates a special
purpose proxy to the primary and replica example provided in the <b>primary-replica</b> example.</p>
<p><b>crunchy-proxy</b> offers a high performance alternative to
pgbouncer and pgpool.</p>
<p>The proxy example copies a configuration file to the PV_PATH
and starts up the <b>crunchy-proxy</b> within a Deployment.
It then reads the configuration file from a <b>/config</b> volume
mount and begins execution.</p>
<p>The proxy will listen on port 5432 as specified in the
configuration file.  The example creates a Service named
<b>crunchy-proxy</b> that you can use to access the configured
PostgreSQL backend containers from the <b>primary-replica</b> example.</p>
<p>SQL <quote>reads</quote> will be sent to the PostgreSQL replica database if your
SQL includes the <b>crunchy-proxy</b> read annotation.  SQL statements
that do not include the read annotation will be sent to the primary
database container within the PostgreSQL cluster.</p>
<p>See this link for details on the <b>crunchy-proxy</b>:
<link url="https://github.com/CrunchyData/crunchy-proxy">https://github.com/CrunchyData/crunchy-proxy</link></p>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_6">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>You can create the proxy by running:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/crunchy-proxy
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>This proxy will listen on localhost:12432.  You can access the
<b>primary-replica</b> cluster through the following:</p>
<code-block>psql -h localhost -p 12432 -U postgres postgres</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_7">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<admonition type="note">If you run the example in minikube, you will need to manually
copy the crunchy-proxy-config.json file to a file on
the minikube named <b>/data/config.json</b>.</admonition>
<p>Start by running the proxy container:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/crunchy-proxy
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Test the proxy by running psql commands via the proxy connection:</p>
<code-block>psql -h crunchy-proxy -U postgres postgres</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_7">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Start by running the proxy container:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/crunchy-proxy
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Test the proxy by running psql commands via the proxy connection:</p>
<code-block>psql -h crunchy-proxy -U postgres postgres</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_pgpool">
<title>pgpool</title>
<p>An example is provided that will run a pgpool container in conjunction with the
primary and replica example (<b>primary-replica</b>) provided above.</p>
<p>You can execute both INSERT and SELECT statements after connecting to pgpool.
The container will direct INSERT statements to the primary and SELECT statements
will be sent round-robin to both primary and replica.</p>
<p>The container creates a default database called <b>userdb</b>, a default user called
<b>testuser</b> and a default password of <b>password</b>.</p>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_7">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>Create the container as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/pgpool
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Enter the following command to connect to the pgpool container that is
mapped to your local port 12003:</p>
<code-block>psql -h localhost -U testuser -p 12003 userdb</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_8">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/primary-replica
./run.sh
cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/pgpool
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>The example is configured to allow the <b>testuser</b> to connect
to the <b>userdb</b> database as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pgpool -U testuser userdb</code-block>
<p>You can view the nodes that pgpool is configured for by running:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pgpool -U testuser userdb -c 'show pool_nodes'</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_8">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Run the following command to deploy the pgpool service:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/pgpool
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Next, you can access the primary replica cluster via the pgpool
service by entering the following command:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pgpool -U testuser userdb
psql -h pgpool -U testuser postgres</code-block>
<p>You can view the nodes that pgpool is configured for by running:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pgpool -U testuser userdb -c 'show pool_nodes'</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_pgbadger">
<title>pgbadger</title>
<p>A pgbadger example is provided that will run a HTTP server that
when invoked, will generate a pgbadger report on a given database.</p>
<p>pgbadger reads the log files from a database to product an HTML report
that shows various PostgreSQL statistics and graphs.</p>
<p>The port utilized for this tool is port 14000 for Docker environments and port 10000
for Kubernetes and Openshift environments.</p>
<p>Additional requirements to build this container include <b>golang</b>. On RHEL 7.2, golang
is found in the <i>server optional</i> repository which needs to be enabled in order to install this dependency.</p>
<p>The container creates a default database called <b>userdb</b>, a default user called
<b>testuser</b> and a default password of <b>password</b>.</p>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_8">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>To run the example:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
modify the run-badger.sh script to refer to the Docker container that you want to run pgbadger against
</list-item>
<list-item>
refer to the container's data directory
</list-item>
<list-item>
start the container that you are referencing
</list-item>
</list>
<p>Then, run the example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/badger
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>After execution, the container will run and provide a simple HTTP
command you can browse to view the report.  As you run queries against
the database, you can invoke this URL to generate updated reports:</p>
<code-block>curl http://127.0.0.1:14000/api/badgergenerate</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_9">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/badger
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>After execution, the container will run and provide a simple HTTP
command you can browse to view the report.  As you run queries against
the database, you can invoke this URL to generate updated reports:</p>
<code-block>curl http://badger:10000/api/badgergenerate</code-block>
<p><b>Tip</b></p>
<p>You can view the database container logs using this command:</p>
<code-block>kubectl logs -c server badger</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_9">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>To run the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/badger
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>After execution, the container will run and provide a simple HTTP
command you can browse to view the report.  As you run queries against
the database, you can invoke this URL to generate updated reports:</p>
<code-block>curl http://badger-example:10000/api/badgergenerate</code-block>
<p>You can view this output in a browser if you allow port forwarding
from your container to your server host using a command like
this:</p>
<code-block>socat tcp-listen:10001,reuseaddr,fork tcp:pg-primary:10000</code-block>
<p>This command maps port 10000 of the service/container to port
10001 of the local server.  You can now use your browser to
see the badger report.</p>
<p>This is a short-cut to expose a service to the external world.
OpenShift would normally configure a router in such a manner where you could
<i>expose</i> the service in an OpenShift way.</p>
<p>The official documentation for installing OpenShift on a router can be found
<link url="https://docs.openshift.com/container-platform/3.6/install_config/router/index.html">here</link>.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_postgres_gis">
<title>postgres-gis</title>
<p>An example is provided that will run a postgres-gis pod/service in Kubernetes/OpenShift and a container in Docker.</p>
<p>The container creates a default database called <b>userdb</b>, a default user called
<b>testuser</b> and a default password of <b>password</b>.</p>
<p>You can view the extensions that postgres-gis has enabled by running the following command (postgis should be listed):</p>
<code-block>psql -h postgres-gis -U testuser userdb -c '\dx'</code-block>
<p>To validate that PostGIS is installed and which version is running, run the command:</p>
<code-block>psql -h postgres-gis -U testuser userdb -c "SELECT postgis_full_version();"</code-block>
<p>You should expect to see output similar to:</p>
<code-block>postgis_full_version
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 POSTGIS="2.4.2 r16113" PGSQL="100" GEOS="3.5.0-CAPI-1.9.0 r4084" PROJ="Rel. 4.8.0, 6 March 2012" GDAL="GDAL 1.11.4, released 2016/01/25" LIBXML="2.9.1" LIBJSON="0.11" TOPOLOGY RASTER
(1 row)</code-block>
<p>To exercise some of the basic PostGIS functionality for validation (in this case defining 2D geometry point - given inputs of longitude and latitude), run the command:</p>
<code-block>psql -h postgres-gis -U testuser userdb -c "select ST_MakePoint(28.385200,-81.563900);"</code-block>
<p>You should expect to see output similar to:</p>
<code-block>                st_makepoint
--------------------------------------------
 0101000000516B9A779C623C40B98D06F0166454C0
(1 row)</code-block>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the pod/container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_9">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>Create the container as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/postgres-gis
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Enter the following command to connect to the postgres-gis container that is
mapped to your local port 12000:</p>
<code-block>psql -h localhost -U testuser -p 12000 userdb</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_10">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/postgres-gis
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>The example is configured to allow the <b>testuser</b> to connect
to the <b>userdb</b> database as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h postgres-gis -U testuser userdb</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_10">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Run the following command to deploy the postgres-gis pod and service:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/postgres-gis
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Next, you can access the postgres-gis pod via the postgres-gis
service by entering the following command:</p>
<code-block>psql -h postgres-gis -U testuser userdb
psql -h postgres-gis -U testuser postgres</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_metrics_collection">
<title>Metrics Collection</title>
<p>You can collect various PostgreSQL metrics from your database
container by running a crunchy-collect container that points
to your database container.</p>
<p>This will start up 3 containers and services:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
Prometheus (<link url="http://crunchy-prometheus:9090">http://crunchy-prometheus:9090</link>)
</list-item>
<list-item>
Prometheus gateway (<link url="http://crunchy-promgateway:9091">http://crunchy-promgateway:9091</link>)
</list-item>
<list-item>
Grafana (<link url="http://crunchy-grafana:3000">http://crunchy-grafana:3000</link>)
</list-item>
</list>
<p>Every 3 minutes the collection container will collect PostgreSQL
metrics and push them to the crunchy-prometheus database.  You
can graph them using the crunchy-grafana container.</p>
<p>If firewalld is enabled in your environment, it may be necessary
to allow the necessary ports through the firewall. This can be
accomplished by the following:</p>
<code-block>firewall-cmd --permanent --new-zone metrics
firewall-cmd --permanent --zone metrics --add-port 9090/tcp
firewall-cmd --permanent --zone metrics --add-port 9091/tcp
firewall-cmd --permanent --zone metrics --add-port 3000/tcp
firewall-cmd --reload</code-block>
<p>All metrics collected by this set of containers are fully described in this <link url="metrics.adoc">document.</link></p>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_10">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>To start this set of containers, run the following:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/metrics
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>An example has been provided that runs a database container
in addition to the associated metrics collection container. Run the
example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/collect
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_11">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/metrics
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>If you want your metrics and dashboards to persist to NFS, run
this script:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/metrics
./run-pvc.sh</code-block>
<p>This example runs a pod that includes a database container and
a metrics collection container. A service is also created for the pod.</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/collect
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>You can view the collect container logs using this command:</p>
<code-block>kubectl logs -c collect primary-collect</code-block>
<p>You can access the database or drive load against it using
this command:</p>
<code-block>psql -h primary-collect -U postgres postgres</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_11">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>First, create the crunchy-metrics pod which contains
the Prometheus data store and the Grafana graphing web application:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/metrics
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Next, start a PostgreSQL pod that has the crunchy-collect container
as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/collect
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_vacuum">
<title>Vacuum</title>
<p>You can perform a PostgreSQL vacuum command by running the crunchy-vacuum
container.  You specify a database to vacuum using environment variables. By default,
it will specify the <b>basic</b> example; you will need to start the <b>basic</b> container
before running <b>vacuum</b>.</p>
<p>The crunchy-vacuum container image exists to allow a DBA a way to run a job either
individually or scheduled to perform a variety of vacuum operations.</p>
<p>This example performs a vacuum on a single table in the primary PostgreSQL
database. The crunchy-vacuum image is executed, passed in
the PostgreSQL connection parameters to the single-primary PostgreSQL
container.  The type of vacuum performed is dictated by the
environment variables passed into the job. Vacuum is controlled via the following
environment variables:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
VAC_FULL - when set to true adds the FULL parameter to the VACUUM command
</list-item>
<list-item>
VAC_TABLE - when set, allows you to specify a single table to vacuum, when
 not specified, the entire database tables are vacuumed
</list-item>
<list-item>
JOB_HOST - required variable is the PostgreSQL host we connect to
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_USER - required variable is the PostgreSQL user we connect with
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_DATABASE - required variable is the PostgreSQL database we connect to
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_PASSWORD - required variable is the PostgreSQL user password we connect with
</list-item>
<list-item>
PG_PORT - allows you to override the default value of 5432
</list-item>
<list-item>
VAC_ANALYZE - when set to true adds the ANALYZE parameter to the VACUUM command
</list-item>
<list-item>
VAC_VERBOSE - when set to true adds the VERBOSE parameter to the VACUUM command
</list-item>
<list-item>
VAC_FREEZE - when set to true adds the FREEZE parameter to the VACUUM command
</list-item>
</list>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_11">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>Run the example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/vacuum
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_12">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/vacuum-job/
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Verify the job is completed:</p>
<code-block>kubectl get job</code-block>
<p>View the docker log of the vacuum job's pod:</p>
<code-block>docker logs $(docker ps -a | grep crunchy-vacuum | cut -f 1 -d' ')</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_12">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Run the example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd ../vacuum-job
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_cron_scheduler">
<title>Cron Scheduler</title>
<p>The crunchy-dba container implements a cron scheduler. The purpose of the crunchy-dba
container is to offer a way to perform simple DBA tasks that occur on some form of
schedule such as backup jobs or running a vacuum on a single PostgreSQL database container
(such as the <b>basic</b> example).</p>
<p>You can either run the crunchy-dba container as a single pod or include the container
within a database pod.</p>
<p>The crunchy-dba container makes use of a Service Account to perform the startup of
scheduled jobs. The Kubernetes Job type is used to execute the scheduled jobs with a Restart
policy of Never.</p>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_kubernetes_13">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>The script to schedule vacuum on a regular schedule is executed through the following
commands:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/dba
./run-vac.sh</code-block>
<p>To run the script for scheduled backups, run the following in the same directory:</p>
<code-block>./run-backup.sh</code-block>
<p>Individual parameters for both can be modified within their respective JSON files;
please see <link url="https://github.com/CrunchyData/crunchy-containers/blob/master/docs/containers.adoc">containers.adoc</link> for a full list of what can be modified.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_pgbouncer">
<title>pgbouncer</title>
<p>The pgbouncer utility can be used to provide a connection pool
to PostgreSQL databases.</p>
<p>This example configures pgbouncer to provide connection pooling
for the primary and pg-replica databases.  It also sets the FAILOVER
environment variable which will cause a failover to be triggered
if the primary database can not be reached.</p>
<p>After triggering the failover, pgbouncer will notice that the primary is not reachable
and will touch the trigger file on the configured replica database to start
the failover.  The pgbouncer container will then reconfigure
pgbouncer to relabel the replica database into the primary database so clients
to pgbouncer will be able to connect to the primary as before the failover.</p>
<p>This example is required to run in conjunction with another container, by default the
<b>primary-replica</b> example.</p>
<p>Additionally, the example assumes you have an NFS share path of /mnt/nfsfileshare/.
NFS is required to mount the pgbouncer configuration files which are
then mounted to /pgconf in the crunchy-pgbouncer container.</p>
<p>If you mount a /pgconf volume, crunchy-postgres will look at that directory
for postgresql.conf, pg_hba.conf, and setup.sql.  If it finds one of them it
will use that file instead of the default files.</p>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_12">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>The pgbouncer example is run as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/pgbouncer
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>To trigger the failover, stop the primary database:</p>
<code-block>docker stop primary</code-block>
<p>To log into the database from the pgbouncer connection pool
you would enter the following using the default password <b>password</b>:</p>
<code-block>psql -h localhost -p 12005 -U testuser primary</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_14">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/pgbouncer
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Connect to the <b>primary</b> and <b>replica</b> databases as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pgbouncer -U postgres primary
psql -h pgbouncer -U postgres replica</code-block>
<p>The names <b>primary</b> and <b>replica</b> are pgbouncer configured names
and don't necessarily have to match the database name in the
actual PostgreSQL instance.</p>
<p>View the pgbouncer log as follows:</p>
<code-block>kubectl log pgbouncer</code-block>
<p>Next, test the failover capability within the crunchy-watch
container using the following:</p>
<code-block>kubectl delete pod primary</code-block>
<p>Take another look at the pgbouncer log and you will see it trigger
the failover to the replica pod.  After this failover
you should be able to execute the command:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pgbouncer -U postgres primary</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_13">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Run the example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/pgbouncer
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>Test the example by killing off the primary database container as follows:</p>
<code-block>oc delete pod primary-dc</code-block>
<p>Then watch the pgbouncer log as follows to confirm it detects the loss of the primary:</p>
<code-block>oc logs pgbouncer</code-block>
<p>After the failover is completed, you should be able to access the new primary using
the primary service as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h primary-dc.openshift.svc.cluster.local -U primary postgres</code-block>
<p>and access the replica as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h replica-dc.openshift.svc.cluster.local -U primary postgres</code-block>
<p>or via the pgbouncer proxy as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pgbouncer.openshift.svc.cluster.local  -U primary primary</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_synchronous_replication">
<title>Synchronous Replication</title>
<p>This example deploys a PostgreSQL cluster with a primary, a synchronous replica, and
an asynchronous replica. The two replicas share the same Service.</p>
<p>Connect to the <b>primarysync</b> and <b>replicasync</b> databases as follows for both the
Kubernetes and OpenShift environments:</p>
<code-block>psql -h primarysync -U postgres postgres -c 'create table test (id int)'
psql -h primarysync -U postgres postgres -c 'insert into test values (1)'
psql -h primarysync -U postgres postgres -c 'table pg_stat_replication'
psql -h replicasync -U postgres postgres -c 'select inet_server_addr(), * from test'
psql -h replicasync -U postgres postgres -c 'select inet_server_addr(), * from test'
psql -h replicasync -U postgres postgres -c 'select inet_server_addr(), * from test'</code-block>
<p>This set of queries will show you the IP address of the PostgreSQL replica
container. Notice the changing IP address due to the round-robin service proxy
being used for both replicas.  The example queries also show that both
replicas are replicating from the primary.</p>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_13">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>To run this example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/sync
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>You can test the replication status on the primary by using the following command
and the password <quote>password</quote>:</p>
<code-block>psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12000 -U postgres postgres -c 'table pg_stat_replication'</code-block>
<p>You should see 2 rows, 1 for the async replica and 1 for the sync replica.  The
sync_state column shows values of async or sync.</p>
<p>You can test replication to the replicas by entering some data on
the primary like this, and then querying the replicas for that data:</p>
<code-block>psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12000 -U postgres postgres -c 'create table foo (id int)'
psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12000 -U postgres postgres -c 'insert into foo values (1)'
psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12002 -U postgres postgres -c 'table foo'
psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12003 -U postgres postgres -c 'table foo'</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_15">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/sync
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_14">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Running the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/sync
./run.sh</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_statefulsets">
<title>Statefulsets</title>
<p>This example deploys a statefulset named <b>pgset</b>.  The statefulset
is a new feature in Kubernetes as of version 1.5 and in OpenShift Origin as of
version 3.5. Statefulsets have replaced PetSets going forward.</p>
<p>This example creates 2 PostgreSQL containers to form the set.  At
startup, each container will examine its hostname to determine
if it is the first container within the set of containers.</p>
<p>The first container is determined by the hostname suffix assigned
by Kubernetes to the pod.  This is an ordinal value starting with <b>0</b>.</p>
<p>If a container sees that it has an ordinal value of <b>0</b>, it will
update the container labels to add a new label of:</p>
<code-block>name=$PG_PRIMARY_HOST</code-block>
<p>In this example, PG_PRIMARY_HOST is specified as <b>pgset-primary</b>.</p>
<p>By default, the containers specify a value of <b>name=pgset-replica</b>.</p>
<p>There are 2 services that end user applications will use to
access the PostgreSQL cluster, one service (pgset-primary) routes to the primary
container and the other (pgset-replica) to the replica containers.</p>
<code-block>$ kubectl get service
NAME            CLUSTER-IP      EXTERNAL-IP   PORT(S)    AGE
kubernetes      10.96.0.1       &lt;none&gt;        443/TCP    22h
pgset           None            &lt;none&gt;        5432/TCP   1h
pgset-primary    10.97.168.138   &lt;none&gt;        5432/TCP   1h
pgset-replica   10.97.218.221   &lt;none&gt;        5432/TCP   1h</code-block>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_kubernetes_16">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Start the example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/statefulset
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>You can access the primary database as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pgset-primary -U postgres postgres</code-block>
<p>You can access the replica databases as follows:</p>
<code-block>psql -h pgset-replica -U postgres postgres</code-block>
<p>You can scale the number of containers using this command, this will
essentially create an additional replica databse:</p>
<code-block>kubectl scale pgset --replica=3</code-block>
<section id="_statefulset_using_dynamic_provisioning">
<title>Statefulset using Dynamic Provisioning</title>
<p>The example in <b>examples/statefulset-dyn</b> is almost an exact copy of the
previous statefulset example; however, this example uses
Dynamic Storage Provisioning to automatically create Persistent
Volume Claims based on StorageClasses.  This Kubernetes feature is
available on Google Container Engine which this example was
tested upon.</p>
<p>You can run the example as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/statefulset-dyn
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>This will create a StorageClass named <b>slow</b> which you can view using:</p>
<code-block>kubectl get storageclass
NAME      TYPE
slow      kubernetes.io/gce-pd</code-block>
<p>The example causes Kube to create the required PVCs automatically:</p>
<code-block>kubectl get pvc
NAME             STATUS    VOLUME                                     CAPACITY   ACCESSMODES   STORAGECLASS   AGE
pgdata-pgset-0   Bound     pvc-06334f6f-371b-11e7-9bda-42010a8000e9   1Gi        RWX           slow           5m
pgdata-pgset-1   Bound     pvc-063795b3-371b-11e7-9bda-42010a8000e9   1Gi        RWX           slow           5m</code-block>
<p>More information on dynamic storage provisioning can be found here:
<link url="https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/storage/persistent-volumes/">https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/storage/persistent-volumes/</link></p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_helm_3">
<title>Helm</title>
<p>This example resides under the $CCPROOT/examples/helm directory. View the README to
run this example using Helm <link url="https://github.com/CrunchyData/crunchy-containers/blob/master/examples/helm/statefulset/README.md">here</link>.</p>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_15">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Build the example:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/statefulset
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>This will create a statefulset named pgset, which will create
2 pods, pgset-0 and pgset-1:</p>
<code-block>oc get statefulset
oc get pod</code-block>
<p>A service is created for the primary and another service for the replica:</p>
<code-block>oc get service</code-block>
<p>The statefulset ordinal value of 0 is used to determine which pod
will act as the PostgreSQL primary, all other ordinal values will
assume the replica role.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_pitr_pitr_point_in_time_recovery">
<title>pitr - PITR (point in time recovery)</title>
<p>This is an example of performing point in time recovery on your database. See the
<link url="pitr.adoc">PITR Documentation</link> for details on PITR concepts and how PITR is implemented
within the Suite.</p>
<p>It takes about 1 minute for the database to become ready for use after initially starting.</p>
<p>This database is created with the ARCHIVE_MODE and ARCHIVE_TIMEOUT
environment variables set.</p>
<admonition type="warning">WAL segment files are written to the /tmp directory. Leaving the example running
for a long time could fill up your /tmp directory.</admonition>
<p>To shutdown the instance and remove the container for each example, run the following:</p>
<code-block>./cleanup.sh</code-block>
<section id="_docker_14">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>Create a database container as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/pitr
./run-primary-pitr.sh</code-block>
<p>Next, we will create a base backup of that database using this:</p>
<code-block>./run-primary-pitr-backup.sh</code-block>
<p>After creating the base backup of the database, WAL segment files are created every 60 seconds
that contain any database changes. These segments are stored in the
/tmp/primary-data/master-wal directory.</p>
<p>Create some data in your database using this command:</p>
<code-block>psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12000 -U postgres postgres -c "select pg_create_restore_point('beforechanges')"
psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12000 -U postgres postgres -c 'create table pitrtest (id int)'
psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12000 -U postgres postgres -c "select pg_create_restore_point('afterchanges')"
psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12000 -U postgres postgres -c "select pg_create_restore_point('nomorechanges')"
psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12000 -U postgres postgres -c "checkpoint"</code-block>
<p>Next, stop the database to avoid conflicts with the WAL files while
attempting to do a restore from them:</p>
<code-block>docker stop primary-pitr</code-block>
<p>The commands above set restore point labels which we can
use to mark the points in the recovery process we want to
reference when creating our restored database.  Points before
and after the test table were made.</p>
<p>Next, let's edit the restore script to use the base backup files
created in the step above.  You can view the backup path name
under the /tmp/backups/primary-pitr-backups/ directory. You will see
another directory inside of this path with a name similar to
<b>2016-09-21-21-03-29</b>.  Copy and paste that value into the
run-restore-pitr.sh script in the <b>BACKUP</b> environment variable.</p>
<p>In order to restore the database before we created test table in the
last command, you'll need uncomment to the RECOVERY_TARGET_NAME label
<b>-e RECOVERY_TARGET_NAME=beforechanges</b> to define the restore target name.
After that, run the script.</p>
<code-block>vi ./run-restore-pitr.sh
./run-restore-pitr.sh</code-block>
<p>The WAL segments are read and applied when restoring from the database
backup.  At this point, you should be able to verify that the
database was restored to the point before creating the test table:</p>
<code-block>psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12001 -U postgres postgres -c 'table pitrtest'</code-block>
<p>This SQL command should show that the pitrtest table does not exist
at this recovery time. The output should be similar to:</p>
<p>PostgreSQL allows you to pause the recovery process if the target name
or time is specified.  This pause would allow a DBA a chance to review
the recovery time/name and see if this is what they want or expect.  If so,
the DBA can run the following command to resume and complete the recovery:</p>
<code-block>psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12001 -U postgres postgres -c 'select pg_xlog_replay_resume()'</code-block>
<p>Until you run the statement above, the database will be left in read-only
mode.</p>
<p>Next, run the script to restore the database
to the <b>afterchanges</b> restore point, do this by updating the
RECOVERY_TARGET_NAME to <b>afterchanges</b>:</p>
<code-block>vi ./run-restore-pitr.sh
./run-restore-pitr.sh</code-block>
<p>After this restore, you should be able to see the test table:</p>
<code-block>psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12001 -U postgres postgres -c 'table pitrtest'
psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12001 -U postgres postgres -c 'select pg_xlog_replay_resume()'</code-block>
<p>Lastly, start a recovery using all of the WAL files. This will get the
restored database as current as possible. To do so, edit the script
to remove the RECOVERY_TARGET_NAME environment setting completely:</p>
<code-block>./run-restore-pitr.sh
sleep 30
psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12001 -U postgres postgres -c 'table pitrtest'
psql -h 127.0.0.1 -p 12001 -U postgres postgres -c 'create table foo (id int)'</code-block>
<p>At this point, you should be able to create new data in the restored database
and the test table should be present.  When you recover the entire
WAL history, resuming the recovery is not necessary to enable writes.</p>
</section>
<section id="_kubernetes_17">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>This example is identical to the OpenShift PITR example; please see below for
details on how the PITR example works.</p>
<p>The only differences are the following:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
paths are <b>$CCPROOT/examples/kube/pitr</b>
</list-item>
<list-item>
JSON and scripts are modified to work with Kubernetes
</list-item>
<list-item>
<b>kubectl</b> commands are used instead of <b>oc</b> commands
</list-item>
<list-item>
database services resolve to <b>default.svc.cluster.local</b> instead
   of <b>openshift.svc.cluster.local</b>
</list-item>
</list>
</section>
<section id="_openshift_16">
<title>OpenShift</title>
<p>Start by running the example database container:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/openshift/pitr
./run-primary-pitr.sh</code-block>
<p>This step will create a database container, <b>primary-pitr</b>.  This
container is configured to continuously write WAL segment files
to a mounted volume (/pgwal).</p>
<p>After you start the database, you will create a base backup
using this command:</p>
<code-block>./run-primary-pitr-backup.sh</code-block>
<p>This will create a backup and write the backup files to a persistent
volume (/pgbackup).</p>
<p>Next, create some recovery targets within the database by running
the SQL commands against the <b>primary-pitr</b> database as follows:</p>
<code-block>./run-sql.sh</code-block>
<p>This will create recovery targets named <b>beforechanges</b>, <b>afterchanges</b>, and
<b>nomorechanges</b>.  It will create a table, <b>pitrtest</b>, between
the <b>beforechanges</b> and <b>afterchanges</b> targets.  It will also run a SQL
CHECKPOINT to flush out the changes to WAL segments.</p>
<p>Next, now that we have a base backup and a set of WAL files containing
our database changes, we can shut down the <b>primary-pitr</b> database
to simulate a database failure.  Do this by running the following:</p>
<code-block>oc delete pod primary-pitr</code-block>
<p>Next, we will create 3 different restored database containers based
upon the base backup and the saved WAL files.</p>
<p>First, we restore prior to the <b>beforechanges</b> recovery target.  This
recovery point is <b>before</b> the <b>pitrtest</b> table is created.</p>
<p>Edit the primary-pitr-restore.json file, and edit the environment
variable to indicate we want to use the <b>beforechanges</b> recovery
point:</p>
<code-block>}, {
"name": "RECOVERY_TARGET_NAME",
"value": "beforechanges"
}, {</code-block>
<p>Then run the following to create the restored database container:</p>
<code-block>./run-restore-pitr.sh</code-block>
<p>After the database has restored, you should be able to perform
a test to see if the recovery worked as expected:</p>
<code-block>psql -h primary-pitr-restore.openshift.svc.cluster.local -U postgres postgres -c 'table pitrtest'
psql -h primary-pitr-restore.openshift.svc.cluster.local -U postgres postgres -c 'create table foo (id int)'
psql -h primary-pitr-restore.openshift.svc.cluster.local -U postgres postgres -c 'select pg_xlog_replay_resume()'
psql -h primary-pitr-restore.openshift.svc.cluster.local -U postgres postgres -c 'create table foo (id int)'</code-block>
<p>The output of these command should show that the <b>pitrtest</b> table is not
present.  It should also show that you can not create a new table
because the database is paused in recovery mode.  Lastly, if you
execute a <b>resume</b> command, it will show that you can now create
a table as the database has fully recovered.</p>
<p>You can also test that if <b>afterchanges</b> is specified, that the
<b>pitrtest</b> table is present but that the database is still in recovery
mode.</p>
<p>Lastly, you can test a full recovery using <b>all</b> of the WAL files, if
you remove the <b>RECOVERY_TARGET_NAME</b> environment variable completely.</p>
<p>The NFS portions of this example depend upon an NFS file
system with the following path configurations be present:</p>
<code-block>/mnt/nfsfileshare
/mnt/nfsfileshare/backups
/mnt/nfsfileshare/WAL</code-block>
<p>Once you recover a database using PITR, it will be in read-only mode.  To
make the database resume as a writable database, run the following
sql command:</p>
<code-block>select pg_xlog_replay_resume();</code-block>
<p>This command changed for PG10 to:</p>
<code-block>postgres=# select pg_wal_replay_resume();</code-block>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_pgaudit">
<title>pgaudit</title>
<p>This example provides an example of enabling pgaudit output.
As of release 1.3, pgaudit is included in the crunchy-postgres
container and is added to the PostgreSQL shared library list in
the postgresql.conf.</p>
<p>Given the numerous ways pgaudit can be configured, the exact
pgaudit configuration is left to the user to define.  pgaudit
allows you to configure auditing rules either in postgresql.conf
or within your SQL script.</p>
<p>For this test, we place pgaudit statements within a SQL script
and verify that auditing is enabled and working.  If you choose
to configure pgaudit via a postgresql.conf file, then you will
need to define your own custom postgresql.conf file and mount
it to override the default postgresql.conf file.</p>
<section id="_docker_15">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>Run the following to create a database container:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/pgaudit
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>This starts a database on port 12005 on localhost.  You can then
run the test script as follows:</p>
<code-block>./test-pgaudit.sh</code-block>
<p>This test executes a SQL file which contains pgaudit configuration
statements as well as executes some basic SQL commands.  These
SQL commands will cause pgaudit to create audit log messages in
the pg_log log file created by the database container.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_docker_swarm">
<title>Docker Swarm</title>
<p>This example shows how to run a primary and replica database
container on a Docker Swarm (v.1.12) cluster.</p>
<p>First, set up a cluster. The Kubernetes libvirt coreos cluster
example works well; see <link url="http://kubernetes.io/docs/getting-started-guides/libvirt-coreos/">coreos-libvirt-cluster.</link></p>
<p>Next, on each node, create the Swarm using these
<link url="https://docs.docker.com/engine/swarm/swarm-tutorial/create-swarm/">Swarm Install instructions.</link></p>
<p>Includes the command on the manager node:</p>
<code-block>docker swarm init --advertise-addr 192.168.10.1</code-block>
<p>Then the command on all the worker nodes:</p>
<code-block> docker swarm join \
     --token SWMTKN-1-65cn5wa1qv76l8l45uvlsbprogyhlprjpn27p1qxjwqmncn37o-015egopg4jhtbmlu04faon82u \
         192.168.10.1.37</code-block>
<p>Before creating Swarm services, for service discovery you need
to define an overlay network to be used by the services you will
create.  Create the network like this:</p>
<code-block>docker network create --driver overlay crunchynet</code-block>
<p>We want to have the primary database always placed on
a specific node. This is accomplished using node constraints
as follows:</p>
<code-block>docker node inspect kubernetes-node-1 | grep ID
docker node update --label-add type=primary 18yrb7m650umx738rtevojpqy</code-block>
<p>In the above example, the kubernetes-node-1 node with ID
18yrb7m650umx738rtevojpqy has a user defined label of <b>primary</b> added to it.
The primary service specifies <b>primary</b> as a constraint when created; this
tells Swarm to place the service on that specific node.  The replica specifies
a constraint of <b>node.labels.type != primary</b> to have the replica
always placed on a node that is not hosting the primary service.</p>
<section id="_docker_16">
<title>Docker</title>
<p>After you set up the Swarm cluster, you can then run this example as follows on the <b>Swarm Manager Node</b>:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/docker/swarm-service
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>You can then find the nodes that are running the primary and replica containers
by:</p>
<code-block>docker service ps primary
docker service ps replica</code-block>
<p>You can also scale up the number of <b>replica</b> containers.</p>
<code-block>docker service scale replica=2
docker service ls</code-block>
<p>Verify you have two replicas within PostgreSQL by viewing the <b>pg_stat_replication</b> table.
The password is <b>password</b> by default when logged into the kubernetes-node-1 host:</p>
<code-block>docker exec -it $(docker ps -q) psql -U postgres -c 'table pg_stat_replication' postgres</code-block>
<p>You should see a row for each replica along with its replication status.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_pg_upgrade">
<title>pg_upgrade</title>
<p>Starting in release 1.3.1, the upgrade container will let
you perform a pg_upgrade on a 9.5 database converting its data
to a 9.6 version.</p>
<p>This example assumes you have run <b>primary-pvc</b> using a PG 9.5 image
such as <b>centos7-9.5.10-1.7.0</b> prior to running this upgrade.</p>
<p>Prior to starting this example, shut down the <b>primary-pvc</b> database
using the <b>examples/kube/primary-pvc/cleanup.sh</b> script.</p>
<p>Prior to running this example, make sure your CCP_IMAGE_TAG
environment variable is using a PG 9.6 image such as <b>centos7-9.6.6-1.7.0</b>.</p>
<p>This will create the following in your Kubernetes environment:</p>
<list>
<list-item>
a Kubernetes Job running the <b>crunchy-upgrade</b> container
</list-item>
<list-item>
a new data directory name <b>primary-upgrade</b> found in the <b>pgnewdata</b>
 PVC
</list-item>
</list>
<section id="_kubernetes_18">
<title>Kubernetes</title>
<p>Start the upgrade as follows:</p>
<code-block>cd $CCPROOT/examples/kube/upgrade
./run.sh</code-block>
<p>If successful, the Job will end with a Successful status. Verify
the results of the Job by examining the Job's pod log:</p>
<code-block>kubectl get pod -a -l job-name=upgrade-job
kubectl logs -l job-name=upgrade-job</code-block>
<p>You can verify the upgraded database by running the
<b>examples/kube/primary-upgrade</b> example. This example will mount the newly created
and upgraded database files. Database tables and data that were in the <b>primary-pvc</b>
test database should be found in the <b>primary-upgrade</b> database.</p>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section id="_legal_notices">
<title>Legal Notices</title>
<p>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 Crunchy Data Solutions, Inc.</p>
<p>CRUNCHY DATA SOLUTIONS, INC. PROVIDES THIS GUIDE <quote>AS IS</quote> WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF NON INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.</p>
<p>Crunchy, Crunchy Data Solutions, Inc. and the Crunchy Hippo Logo are trademarks of Crunchy Data Solutions, Inc.</p>
</section>
</doc>
